A Guide to the Austin Kennell Papers 1968-1999
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Austin Kennell Papers 1968-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10553-ak
ca. 2,000 items (6 Hollinger boxes, ca. 2.5 linear feet)
This addition to the Austin Kennell Papers, 1968-1999, consists of correspondence, files pertaining to the American Rhododendron Society, newsclippings, nursery catalogs, and videocassette tape recordings.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by Austin Kennell, Afton, Virginia, on October 13, 1999.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the papers of Austin Kennell, of Afton, Virginia, 1968-1999, consists of correspondence with other well-known rhododendron enthusiasts and nurseries; a few files pertaining to the American Rhododendron Society, including an information notebook, the endowment fund, membership list, trivia questions, and the seed exchange; and files concerning a proposed rhododendron tour to Scotland, England and Denmark (1991); news clippings pertaining to Kennell and his rhododendron activities; printed nursery catalogs; two copies of "Fundamentals of Rhododendron & Azalea Culture"; and three videocassette tape recordings (videocassette 0051), including one about the public gardens of Georgia, and two concerning the Mid-Atlantic Chapter, ARS, convention in Williamsburg, Virginia (1988), and the Norfolk Botanical Garden and the McDonald Garden.
Prominent nurseries and other correspondents include: Beasley Transplant Nursery, Bovees Nursery, Briggs Nursery, Bull Valley Rhododendron Nursery, Cardinal Nursery, Roy W. Clark of Rainbow Gardens, Hillside Rhododendron Gardens, James Harris Nursery, Caroline Gable, Carl Adam Lehmann, Eveline and Howard Pilkington, Orlando S. Pride, Roslyn Nursery, Ross B. Davis, Jr., Anthony Shammarello, and the Winterthur Museum. Many of the correspondence files also contain nursery catalogs.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by subject within each series.
Contents List
- Correspondence 1970-1999 (Box 1-5)
  - Bjarke & Anita Aunsbjorn 1976-1989, n.d., 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Beasley Transplant Nursery 1980-1997, n.d., 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Bovees Nursery 1968-1977, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Bovees Nursery 1978-1995, n.d., 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Briggs Nursery 1983-1997, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Bull Valley Rhododendron Nursery 1980-1995 (Box 2)
  - Cardinal Nursery 1988-1996, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Roy W. Clark, Rainbow Gardens 1974-1996, n.d., 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Ross B. Davis, Jr. 1976-1994, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Caroline Gable 1970-1995, n.d., 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Heritage Plantation of Sandwich 1974-1981, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Hillside Rhododendron Gardens 1977-1995, n.d. (Box 4)
  - James Harris Nursery 1979-1990, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Carl Adam Lehmann 1975-1992, n.d., 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Eveline & Howard Pilkington 1983-1994, n.d., 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Orlando S. Pride 1968-1989, n.d., 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Roslyn Nursery 1989-1999, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Roslyn Nursery (Catalogs) 1985-1999 (Box 5)
  - Anthony Shammarello 1978-1983, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Winterthur Museum, Garden & Library 1983-1997, n.d. (Box 5)
- American Rhododendron Society & Topical Files 1985-1998 (Box 6)
  - American Rhododendron Society--Endowment Fund 1997-1998
  - American Rhododendron Society Information Notebook 1985 July
  - American Rhododendron Society Membership List 1998
  - American Rhododendron Society Seed Exchange 1998
  - American Rhododendron Society--Trivia Questions 1994, n.d.
  - "Fundamentals of Rhododendron & Azalea Culture" n.d.
  - Newsclippings re Austin Kennell 1987-1989, n.d.
  - Rhododendron Tour (Proposed) Denmark 1989-1991, n.d.
  - Rhododendron Tour (Proposed) England 1988-1991, n.d.
  - Rhododendron Tour (Proposed) Scotland 1989-1991, n.d.